<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike and Eesa</title>
    <description>The adventures of a pilot, his wife, and their dog.
</description>
    <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mikeandeesa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:15:10 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:15:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Epic Adventure Out West Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us on an epic week-long trip from Aurora Illinois to Placerville California and back. In this first installment, we head out to Lincoln Nebraska (KLNC) from our home base at KARR while dodging thunderstorms and planning our next leg to the famous Casa Bonita in Denver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/byaFdLrBAbQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/trip-report/2020/09/28/epic-west-trip-part-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/trip-report/2020/09/28/epic-west-trip-part-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>trip-report</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Flew A Military Jet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Holy crap! I flew a military trainer jet! It was amazing! It was also spendy… but what’s the price of fun?! Anyway, here’s the video. Thanks for checking it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u5E4JbSmXQI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/acro/2020/08/25/i-flew-a-jet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/acro/2020/08/25/i-flew-a-jet.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>acro</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Off to Annual for 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well its that time of year again. Time to take the plane in for her annual inspection. I don’t have many squawks to have addressed because I generally try to stay on top of things and have them fixed as soon as we find them. However, annual time is a great time to have those airframe upgrades you’ve been thinking about done while the plane is down and taken apart anyway. So this time around, I’m having a couple things added which you’ll find out about when I pick the plane up. I’ll post a video of what we got done while it was in for annual. I may even go through my bill to shed further light on exactly how much it costs to maintain a classic retractable gear bird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, come along with me on a quick and relaxing solo flight up to Lake in the Hills (3CK) to drop the plane off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-video&quot;&gt;The Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ml1wHhIS2aI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/2020/07/14/off-to-annual.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/2020/07/14/off-to-annual.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Flying to Kalkaska for the 4th</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eesa and I were feeling like we needed to get away for the long weekend. So we loaded up the plane and flew up to the family cabin in Kalkaska Michigan to visit family and just get away from it all for a few days. Come join us on the trip as we made our way from KARR to Y89 in blistering heat and humidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-video&quot;&gt;The Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HPpjRSwAWM8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/trip-report/2020/07/07/flying-to-pure-michigan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/trip-report/2020/07/07/flying-to-pure-michigan.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>trip-report</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Got a New Best Tugs Tug!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OMG! A new Tug! Not just any tug either… we got a Best Tugs tug!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did we get a new tug? Well, we were planning on moving to New Jersey early this year. We moved all of our hangar stuff out to our new hangar at Morristown Airport (KMMU). This included our tug. Since then, a lot of stuff has changed for us and our move has been infinitely delayed. So we don’t have a tug here in Aurora. After discussing it with Eesa, it was decided that we should get a new tug. She convinced me to go full in on a Best Tugs tug. I spoke to Paxton Patey on the phone and he convinced me that the A3 was going to be perfect for us. So I ordered it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about the Tug or order one for yourself: https://www.besttugs.com/pages/a-3-info&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-video&quot;&gt;The Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/N-kH0hTq7pY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/aircraft-ownership/2020/07/01/we-got-a-new-tug.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/aircraft-ownership/2020/07/01/we-got-a-new-tug.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>aircraft-ownership</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>VLOG Episode 3 -- Landings, Landings, Landings!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I was pretty disappointed in my spot landing skills. It really weighed on me and I couldn’t get it out of my head. I needed to prove to myself that I actually &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do them consistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew my problem was that I was coming in with way too much energy to bleed off in ground effect. So I pulled out the ‘ol POH and looked up the suggested approach speed. It turns out I absolutely was coming in too hot. The book approach speed is 70 knots. I typically come in over the threshold at around 80 knots. That extra 10 knots equals a bunch of extra energy. I attribute this to all the instrument training over the past year. I typically fly a 90 knot approach profile. This means that I’m coming down the glideslope at 90 knots with no flaps and gear down. When I break out, I pull the power back and dump the flaps to slow down as much as possible on short final. The issue here is that the Deb doesn’t slow down quickly, so when you are practicing to minimums, you are 200 feet above the ground and over the fence when you start to slow down. This results in floating over the threshold at 80 knots. My brain has gotten very used to that sight picture, the feel of the controls, and general speed coming in. So to slow it down to 70 knots was a challenge and, at first, felt very very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the VLOG, I did 1.5 hours of flying and a total of 11 full stop landings. I focused on nailing my approach speed of 70 knots over the fence and really retraining my brain to normalize the mushier feel of the controls and the change in general sensations and sight picture. I also have an Angle of Attack (AoA) indicator, and I used that to help dial in and validate the book speed. It was uncomfortable at first, but I eventually got used to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, I proved to myself that I can consistently make my spot landings happen, AND that the book speed is accurate. (Those Beechcraft engineers apparently knew what they were doing.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-video&quot;&gt;The Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/f_Ya8Lj2pLE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/training/2020/06/26/commercial-vlog-ep-3-landings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/training/2020/06/26/commercial-vlog-ep-3-landings.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>training</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Commercial Training VLOG Episode 2 -- Solo Practice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright so that last VLOG was a bit of disaster… I can’t believe I forgot to plug the camera in. Doh! Anyway, this video has actual flying content, I promise :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the VLOG, I’m heading out to do some solo practice of the commercial maneuvers I learned over the weekend. I did a few Chandelles, Steep Turns, Steep Spirals, and a ton of landings. I have a ton of work to do still to fine tune these to the commercial standards, but hey… we all start somewhere right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OMG it was a hot day too.. The air didn’t cool off until I was like 6,000 feet above the ground.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-video&quot;&gt;The Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2SyCVig_XPM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/training/2020/06/18/first-comm-solo-practice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/training/2020/06/18/first-comm-solo-practice.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>training</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Commercial Training VLOG Episode 1 -- The Beginning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whoa boy, more training! That’s right, I’ve decided that maybe now is a good time to start learning how to fly a plane like professional pilot. With all this social distancing and closed social gatherings going on right now, I figured I’m not going to be going many places this summer. Why not scratch the flying itch with some more training? I mean, I’ve spent an amount of money on aviation that I’m not ready to admit. I might as well take it to the point where, if things get crazy, I can make some money with it. It also helps that I’m already qualified in terms of aeronautical experience, so it’s just a matter of learning how to fly the maneuvers and fine tuning my skills to pass the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-video&quot;&gt;The Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1eJDJixqmz0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/training/2020/06/15/starting-my-commercial-training.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/training/2020/06/15/starting-my-commercial-training.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>training</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mom's First Flight in a Small Plane</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My mom has never flown with me and has been asking to go on a flight ever since I got my PPL ticket. As part of my week long vacation visiting family and friends in Florida, I thought it would be a perfect time to take her up in the Debonair. The problem was that the only day we could do it was a bit gusty and because of that, we were going to see some light to moderate turbulence at the lower altitudes. After ~telling~ warning her about this several times, she still wanted to go. So we loaded up the plane for a little scenic tour of where I grew up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-plan&quot;&gt;The Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to take off out of KBKV and do a fly over and a few circuits around my grandparent’s house. Then we would head to the coast and fly along the coast line down to overfly my Mom’s house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the aerial tour and some photography, we would head down to Venice airport and get lunch on the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we would fly back up the coast and back to KBKV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It did go as planned…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew we would need to stay low to go under the KTPA class Bravo shelf, but it looked like we could get above the big bumps without needing to get into the Class Bravo space… I was wrong. Just watch the video to see how it goes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-video&quot;&gt;The Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NgppXT-jHGM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/trip-report/2020/01/28/moms-first-flight.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/trip-report/2020/01/28/moms-first-flight.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>trip-report</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Avionics are Squealing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh no! What’s that loud squealing sound coming from the panel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out the turn coordinator starting making a loud squealing noise after I landed from a long cross country flight. So in today’s video, we’re heading up to Finefield Aviation to have them take a look and swap it out. I have an instrument checkride coming up and I really don’t need the thing crapping out in the middle of the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BsIKY78OiCo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;spoiler&lt;/em&gt;: As all things in maintenance go… the thing stopped making noises promptly at the threat of a mechanic looking at it and as a result, we’re not going to change it out because it seems perfectly fine now after the flight up to 3CK… They will be ordering a replacement to have have in their inventory for when the thing actually does decide to retire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.mikeandeesa.com/aircraft-ownership/2019/08/31/squeeky-turn-coordinator.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mikeandeesa.com/aircraft-ownership/2019/08/31/squeeky-turn-coordinator.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>aircraft-ownership</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
